<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nix on Martin Baillie</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/tags/nix/</link><description>Recent content in nix on Martin Baillie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>© Martin Baillie</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 16:21:00 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martin.baillie.id/tags/nix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avoiding Libinput Hysteresis on a ThinkPad</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/avoiding-libinput-hysteresis-on-a-thinkpad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 16:21:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/avoiding-libinput-hysteresis-on-a-thinkpad/</guid><description>Making a touchpad work on Linux as well as it does on macOS/Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s a problem as old as time itself, or at least as old as the &amp;ldquo;year of Linux on the desktop&amp;rdquo; meme.
The days of calibrating obscure values that I don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand on the old X11 synaptics driver were supposed to be a thing of the past with libinput, and to be fair they have been, for the most part.</description></item><item><title>Your Local Deserves CI, too</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/your-local-deserves-ci-too/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 15:01:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/your-local-deserves-ci-too/</guid><description>Nix Early last year, after teetering on the edge for a while, I finally took the plunge into the world of Nix. It always seemed to be the logical conclusion to my declarative over imperative leanings and it has not disappointed.
I would classify myself as a semi-retired OS bikeshedder these days. I no longer obsess over ricing my prompt nor switch tiling WMs like they&amp;rsquo;re going out of style. Instead, my prompt is a simple exit code coloured semi-colon and I spend the majority of time in either Firefox or Emacs (+vterm).</description></item><item><title>Tailscale Support for NixOS</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/tailscale-support-for-nixos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 18:24:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/tailscale-support-for-nixos/</guid><description>I have been continuing to run with Tailscale instead of hand-cranked WireGuard on various devices, including my daily driver ThinkPad which runs my other favourite OS—NixOS!
However, until now the configuration was not particularly idiomatic due to there being no upstream Tailscale Nix expressions in nixpkgs.
As it transpired, Dan Anderson of Tailscale is also a NixOS user and with his support I was able to shepherd in a quick PR to introduce a Tailscale module.</description></item></channel></rss>