<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>github on Martin Baillie</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in github on Martin Baillie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>© Martin Baillie</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 15:01:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martin.baillie.id/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Your Local Deserves CI, too</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/your-local-deserves-ci-too/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 15:01:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/your-local-deserves-ci-too/</guid><description>Nix Early last year, after teetering on the edge for a while, I finally took the plunge into the world of Nix. It always seemed to be the logical conclusion to my declarative over imperative leanings and it has not disappointed.
I would classify myself as a semi-retired OS bikeshedder these days. I no longer obsess over ricing my prompt nor switch tiling WMs like they&amp;rsquo;re going out of style. Instead, my prompt is a simple exit code coloured semi-colon and I spend the majority of time in either Firefox or Emacs (+vterm).</description></item><item><title>Ephemeral GitHub Tokens via HashiCorp Vault</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/ephemeral-github-tokens-via-hashicorp-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 08:39:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/ephemeral-github-tokens-via-hashicorp-vault/</guid><description>UPDATE: The plugin described in this fieldnote was recently demoed at HashiCorp&amp;rsquo;s Hashitalks 2021.
GitHub I have found that performing automation against GitHub APIs often necessitates the creation of OAuth Tokens (nb. GitHub refers to these as Personal Access Tokens or PATs). These tokens are tied to a user account, have very coarsely-scoped permissions and do not expire.
The more automation-savvy users in an organisation will likely have created many such tokens with powerful permissions which are being neither rotated nor deleted.</description></item></channel></rss>