<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emacs on Martin Baillie</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/tags/emacs/</link><description>Recent content in emacs on Martin Baillie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><copyright>© Martin Baillie</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 15:18:00 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martin.baillie.id/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Emacs TRAMP over AWS SSM APIs</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/emacs-tramp-over-aws-ssm-apis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 15:18:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/emacs-tramp-over-aws-ssm-apis/</guid><description>Cattle not pets The majority of AWS EC2 I need to operate these days are members of Kubernetes clusters. For remote access to them I&amp;rsquo;m more commonly authenticating to the Kube API to spawn a privileged ephemeral debugger pod rather than accessing the host directly. I have little need for host access even for the remaining minority of ancillary EC2 services I&amp;rsquo;m responsible for because all the observability pillars are pulled or pushed somewhere else, and if something is misbehaving or needing replaced I&amp;rsquo;m more likely to shoot it than debug or patch it.</description></item><item><title>Emacs Evil Motion Training</title><link>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/evil-motion-training-for-emacs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 10:33:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://martin.baillie.id/wrote/evil-motion-training-for-emacs/</guid><description>I made the switch to Emacs last year after having been a resolute vim user ever since I dual booted Slackware on my family&amp;rsquo;s first computer as an early teen.
Needless to say the power of the Emacs pseudo lisp machine quickly opened my eyes. I immediately lunged into consolidating practically all my text use cases sans browsing into Emacs: programming, note taking, RSS, mail, git porcelain, GitHub PRs and issues, IRC/Slack.</description></item></channel></rss>